May I come in?
主任
regarding our basketball team members,
关于我们班篮球队队员
if they failed three subjects,
三科不及格
they're not allowed to play.
就不能上场比赛的事
I'd like to ask for one more chance
我想请您再给他们
for them.
一次机会
Please, sir,
请老师
give us one more chance.
再给我们一次机会
Why should I?
理由呢
It's the same for the entire grade.
全年级都一样
Why do you have to be so special?
你们班得特殊
I can vouch for them.
我可以为他们担保
Ling Dong, let me remind you,
凌冬 我提醒你啊
I don't think you should
这种事情
get involved in this.
我不建议你参与其中
Sir,
主任
as Lan Jinghui's uncle
我作为兰靖灰的二表舅
and also
同样也是
the leader of his study group,
学习小组的组长
I should be responsible for his
应该为他的学习成绩
academic performance.
负责
So I guarantee
所以我保证
that by the time of the finals,
在期末考试的时候
Lan Jinghui can advance
兰靖灰同学的成绩
by 100 places.
可以前进一百名
Please give him a shot.
请您给他一次机会吧
100? Are you nuts?
一百名 你疯了
I have that confidence in you.
我对你有这个信心
Right, 100.
没错 一百名
Do you realize
兰靖灰 你知不知道
how many people a single point
咱们学校一分
can surpass in our school?
可以压倒多少人
With your current grades,
以你现在的成绩
it's almost an
几乎是
impossible task.
不可能完成的任务
Sir,
主任
just give me a shot.
您就给我这次机会
I can definitely pull this off.
我一定可以
Ling Dong, can he do it?
凌冬 他可以吗
Absolutely.
当然
It seems like in your basketball team,
好像你们篮球队
besides Lan Jinghui,
除了兰靖灰之外
some others
还有几个人
don't meet the requirements, right?
不符合要求吧
That goes for the others too.
其他人也一样
Fine.
行
I'd love to see what you've got.
我还真想看看你的本事
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
just show me your best shot.
这段时间表现给我看吧
Go back to the classroom.
回教室去吧
Thank you, sir.
谢谢主任
Ling Dong.
凌冬
Pigeons secrete milk to feed their young,
家鸽分泌鸽乳哺喂幼鸽
and chicks learns from the hen
和小鸡跟随母鸡
scratching the ground for worms to eat.
用爪扒地索食
Which one
哪一个
is directly related to pituitary function?
跟垂体功能直接有关
Pigeons feeding the young is due to
家鸽喂小鸽子
the pituitary secretion of prolactin,
是因为垂体分泌催乳素
while chicks are just learning.
而小鸡只是学习行为
Got it.
明白了
Ling Dong, what about this one?
凌冬 这个呢 这个呢
Can chlorine gas produce
氯气能不能生成
sulfur monochloride?
氯化硫单质
Yes.
是可以的
It can directly combine
氯气可以和大多数
with most non-metallic elements,
非金属单质直接化合
including sulfur.
其中就包括硫单质
It can produce sulfur chloride,
可以生成二氯化二硫
and sulfur dichloride
氯气过量时
when chlorine is in excess.
可以生成二氯化硫
Cool.
好
Ling Dong, today's physics class on
凌冬 今天物理课上的
universal gravitation,
万有引力
I didn't quite understand.
我有点没听明白
That's simple!
这个简单
I got it.
我听明白了
There is an attraction
两个物体之间
between two objects.
存在着一种吸引作用
And it exists
这种吸引作用
among all
普遍存在于
in the universe.
宇宙万物之间
This is called universal gravitation.
这就叫作这个万有引力
Ling Dong, is that right?
凌冬 是这样吗
Mostly correct.
基本没问题
For such simple questions,
以后这种简单的问题
no need to bother him.
不用麻烦他
Just come to me.
麻烦我
Isn't that Lan Jinghui?
这不是兰靖灰吗
All in here, huh?
都在啊
Did you all fail the midterm?
都不及格
You're all screwed, aren't you?
你说你们这怎么办啊
You can't even pass your midterm.
文化课都过不了
How are you gonna compete with us
怎么跟我们班
in the tournament?
打篮球赛啊
Shouldn't you strive for
这德智体美劳
for comprehensive development,
不得全面发展吗
huh?
是不是
Peng, we didn't pass either.
鹏哥 咱们也没及格呀
Ling Dong,
凌冬
could you help me
这个你帮我看下呗
with this?
这个题怎么解
Which one?
哪题
Here, the first one.
这个 这个 第一个
That's it for today's lesson.
今天的课就上到这儿
I've covered a lot of stuff.
内容比较多
Make sure that you take time
大家回去以后
to review it.
再温习一下
Class dismissed.
下课
Stand up.
起立
Goodbye, sir.
老师再见
Mr. Guo,
郭老师
I have some other stuff
我最近可能有一些
going on recently.
其他的事情
So, I don't have time
暂时没有时间
for the competition class.
来上物理竞赛课
Has your class advisor been informed?
你们班主任老师知道吗
Yes, she has.
方老师已经知道了
OK, then.
那行吧
I'll give you the learning materials
我会把这段时间的资料
for your absence.
给你一份
Just study on your own.
你回家仔细看看
Come to me when needed.
有什么问题来问我
Thank you, sir.
好 谢谢老师
Ling Dong.
凌冬
I need to have a conversation with you.
我要和你好好谈一下
Why do you...
为什么
You can't fool me...
你别以为我不知道
I know what's going on.
其实我知道
I'm aware why you dropped out.
你为什么退出竞赛班
I just want you
我只是想让你
to tell me the reason in person.
亲口告诉我 为什么
Mr. President, I don't need
我没必要什么事情
to report everything to you, right?
都跟你汇报吧 陈主席
Don't call me that.
不要叫我主席
Since you hang out with
你既然和兰靖灰
students like Lan Jinghui,
那样的同学混在一起
you don't take me,
你就没有
the president of the student union,
把我这个学生会主席
seriously.
放在眼里
He is gonna drag you down,
这样会影响你的
do you know that?
你知不知道
It seems to
影不影响我
have nothing to do with you.
好像跟你也没关系吧
You're definitely wrong!
关系大了
Listen,
我告诉你 凌冬
in the entire grade,
整个高二年级
only you and I,
只有我和你
the two of us,
我们两个人
can become real
才能成为真正的
academic rivals.
学习上的竞争对手
If you choose
你要是自甘堕落
to ruin your future,
自毁前程的话
then you're welcome to do so.
那就别怪我不客气了
How about this,
那这样吧
let's make a bet.
我们打个赌
On what?
赌什么
At the end of this term,
这学期期末
I'll make Lan Jinghui
我让兰靖灰的成绩
advance by 100 places.
前进一百名
And you just need to advance by 1.
而你 前进一名 怎么样
You're so full of yourself.
凌冬 你过分了
Seriously, Ling Dong.
真的过分了 凌冬
Who does he think he is?
太过分了吧
C'mon!
来
Lower yourself, don't rush it.
重心放低 不着急
Take a breath before you shoot.
喘口气再投
Alright!
好嘞
You got it!
有了
Come on.
来
All objects are subject
所有的物体都受到一个
to an unchanging force,
恒定不变的力的作用
and the direction of initial velocity
且初速度方向
is not in a straight line
与这个力
with this force,
不在一条直线上
then the object's trajectory
那么物体的运行轨迹
is a parabola.
就是一条抛物线
Jinghui, what's he talking about?
灰哥 说啥呢
Beats me.
不知道
Parabola?
抛物线
In the air, the basketball
篮球在空中
is only affected by gravity,
仅受到重力的作用
with its size and direction unchanged,
并且大小方向不变
and the direction of initial velocity
而且初速度的方向
is not collinear with gravity.
与重力不共线
Then the basketball's
那么篮球
trajectory in the air
在空中的运动轨迹
is a parabola.
就是一条抛物线
Once you understand the principle,
只要知道了其中的原理
your shooting percentage will increase.
命中率就会提高很多
Dude,
同桌
I didn't expect
真看不出来
you are this good.
你还有这两下子
This represents the essence verified
这都是无数的科学前辈
by countless predecessors.
验证出来的精华
If we apply it to
如果我们运用到
the basketball game,
实战当中
it will be very helpful
那么对提高命中率
in improving shooting.
是有很大帮助的
It could do just that?
还能提高命中率
You've got to explain it to me,
那你给我好好讲讲
about that
这是个什么
parabola principle.
什么抛物线原理
In the math class this afternoon,
下午数学课
we'll learn quadratic functions,
讲二次函数
which will cover
其中会讲到
this.
这方面的知识
You'd better pay attention to that.
最好好好地听一下啊
Sure, sure.
我知道 我知道
Listen to me,
你听我说
since you have
凌冬同学
such a solid base of
既然你有这么丰富的
knowledge and expertise,
知识储备和专业知识
how about
那不如这样
you become our
你来当我们副教练
assistant coach?
对不对
Your knowledge, and my skills...
你有知识 我有技术
Let's join forces.
我们强强联合一下
We'll be invincible, right?
是不是无敌 对不对
- Yes! - Exactly.
对 就是 对啊
Hey, you...
不是 不是
don't just go.
别走啊
Can you give me a straight answer?
行不行给个痛快话吧
Assistant coach?
副教练
Because I'm the head coach.
因为我是主教练嘛
Wait...
不是 不是 不是
alright...
你看这样
you'll be
主教练
the head coach.
就你是主教练了好不好
And we all listen to you,
你说什么是什么
okay?
可不可以
It depends on your effort.
那看你表现喽
Hey, you want to see my effort,
不 你看我表现
then why are you leaving?
你为什么要走啊
Wait,
不是
at least teach a couple
你至少留下来教两招
of moves.
对不对
You're the head coach,
你就是主教练啊
correct?
你
Slow down.
不 你这么着急
Where are you going?
你能去哪儿
This is your first day being a head coach.
你今天第一天上班
You can't just abandon your post.
你就下岗了
Hey, just stay.
不是 你先留下来
Let's take a look
咱们来看一下
at this equation.
这个标准方程式
Y^2 = 2P.
Y的平方等于2P
I've drawn a diagram for you.
我给大家画了一个图
There is a point F
平面内有一条点F
and a line L.
和一条直线L
The points that are equidistant from them
它们的距离的相等的点
are called the parabola.
就叫作轨迹的抛物线
So the fixed point F
那么定点F呢
is called the focus of the parabola.
就叫作抛物线的焦点
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
do you have any questions?
你有什么问题吗
No.
没有
I think you've
我认为方老师
made it quite clear.
你讲得特别好
As if I've opened the door
仿佛自己开启了
to a new world.
新世界的大门
Good, sit down. Let's continue.
好 你坐下继续听课
Guys,
同学们
I've already written down
我刚刚已经把它的
the formula of
标准方程的焦点的公式
the equation for the focus.
已经写下来了
You can take a good look
大家可以好好看一下
and take notes.
做一下笔记
Review everything you've learned
回去以后好好回顾一下
today.
这节课的内容
You should read it through,
你最好先把原文看一遍
and then...
然后找出这个
This type of problem...
这种阅读理解
Guys,
大家注意
look at this one.
这道题
For an electron to transition from
一个电子从基态
the ground state to an excited state,
被激发到激发态
it requires 9eV of energy.
需要9eV的能量
What wavelength
那么
of light is needed for this transition?
跃迁需要什么波长的光
Can anyone
哪位同学
come up and solve this?
可以上来做这道题
Sir, my name is Ling Dong.
老师 我叫凌冬
Ling Dong,
凌冬
do you mind waking Lan Jinghui up?
你叫一下兰靖灰
The teacher is calling.
老师叫你
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
come up and work on this one.
你上来做一下这道题
What? You don't know how to do it?
怎么 不会做啊
"ε = hv"
像这道公式
can be used
ε=hv
to calculate the energy
就可以用来计算
required for an electron
一个电子被光
to be excited by light from the
从基态激发到激发态
ground state to the excited state.
所需的能量
ε = hv?
ε=hv
Right.
对
Even Lan Jinghui knows how to do it.
兰靖灰都会做
Unbelievable.
不会吧
C'mon,
不是吧
I can't even do it myself.
我都不会做
Lan Jinghui got the answer right.
兰靖灰同学回答得正确
Return to your seat.
回去吧
Light is a form of electromagnetic waves
光也是一种电磁波
which consist
而电磁波
of energy quanta.
是由能量子构成的
Each quantum
每一个能量子
carries an energy
所携带的能量
of Hv,
都是Hv
which is Planck's hypothesis.
这就是普朗克假说
"V" stands for frequency,
这里的v指代的是频率
and "H"...
H
Is anyone interested in
有没有人要报名
the cheerleading squad?
啦啦队的
Just come to us for signup.
快来小画这儿报名
Xiao Xiaohua is gonna lead?
她当队长啊
Can she handle it?
她行不行啊
She even won an award
肖小画参加才艺大赛
at the talent competition.
都获奖了
There's no doubt she can do this.
有什么不行的
That was all thanks to Ling Dong.
上次还不是因为有凌冬
Me! Count me in!
我报名 我报名
Me too!
我也报 我也报
Wait, I'm coming!
我也要报 我也要报
Qingtian, I want to...
晴天 我也可
Nah, you're a boy.
你不行 你是男孩
Hey, guys...
你们这些人
Count me in then.
那 那把我也算上
We didn't ask you...
可没有人求你啊
I'm just anxious to ensure
那 那我还不是怕你们
everything goes well...
跳得太差
I hate to see our class get embarrassed.
丢我们五班的人吗
Shu is a ballerina.
姝姝可是学芭蕾的
She's got a great figure.
形体好着呢
But I'm not so good at choreography.
不过我编舞可不太好
What should we do?
那怎么办
Wait, I've got someone in mind.
等等 我想到一个人
She'll do fine.
她一定可以
Mengyu,
梦予
I knew I'd find you here.
我就知道你会在这儿
I don't know why,
也不知道怎么了
but lately,
最近没事
I just like to hang out in here.
就喜欢来天台发呆
What's up?
有什么事吗
The basketball tournament
咱们班篮球队
is coming soon.
不是马上要比赛了吗
I'd like to invite you to join
我想邀请你
our cheerleading squad.
加入我们啦啦队
Why me?
你为什么会来找我呢
Do you really trust me
你就真的放心
to lead the team?
我来带队啊
You know,
你也知道
besides being a lousy singer
我除了五音不全以外
I'm also uncoordinated.
四肢也不协调
What if we get laughed at
万一被别的班啦啦队
by other squads?
笑话怎么办
Do you really need me?
你们真的需要我吗
This isn't what I know about you.
做事这么犹豫不决
You used to be so decisive.
可不是我认识的徐梦予
Alright, I'm in.
好吧 我答应你
But let's get one thing straight.
不过事先说好
You all
我参加啦啦队
have to listen to me.
就得都听我的
The music, costumes, and dance
音乐 服装 舞蹈
should be carefully designed.
都要好好设计一下
OK, it's a deal.
好 一言为定
Deal.
一言为定
Up, down,
四二三四
exactly,
五六七八
5, 2, 3, 4,
五二三四
6, 2, 3, 4...
六二三四
Alright, look at this one.
好 大家看这题
Given that A is greater than 0,
已知A大于0
B is less than 0,
B小于0
and A is not equal to B...
且A不等于B
You are so sweet!
你也太贴心
Go on, pass them!
快去吧 快分吧
Go ahead.
快分了吧
This one is for you.
给你的
Thanks.
谢了
Hey, Qingtian...
晴天
Jia Letian.
贾乐天
Nope...
不知道
I don't know.
我不知道
Alright,
好
I'll explain it again.
那我再给大家讲一下
2, 2, 3, 4...
二二三四
Xiaohua, you're
小画 你这个动作
uncoordinated.
不协调啊
Shift your weight back.
这个动作重心往后移
6, 7, 8,
六七八
2, 2, 3, 4,
二二三四
5, 6, 7...
五六七
Mr. Zhao!
赵老师
- Ms. Fang? - You got a minute?
方老师 你有空吗
Sure.
有空啊
Here's the thing.
是这样
Could you do me a favour?
我呢 有一点点小忙
Not a big deal.
想让你帮一下
No worries. What is it?
方老师有什么事
Be my guest.
尽管开口
The basketball
这不马上
tournament is coming up soon.
要篮球比赛了吗
If it's convenient for you,
所以我想请你
could you
如果有时间的话
possibly give some coaching
能不能单独指导一下
to Class 5?
我们五班
Oh, about that...
这事啊
Is there a problem?
不好办
Ms. Fang,
方老师
this raises an issue
这个牵扯到一个
of fairness.
公平性问题
If I only help
我要是只帮五班
Class 5,
不帮其他班
it wouldn't be fair, would it?
说出也不太好听啊
That's true.
也是
Alright then, thanks anyway.
算了 行 那我先走了
Take care.
你慢忙
Ms. Fang,
方老师
let me think about it.
那我再想想办法
5, 6, 7, 8...
五六七八
1, 2, 3, 4,
一二三四
2, 2, 3, 4,
二二三四
3, 2, 3, 4,
三二三四
4, 2, 3, 4,
四二三四
5, 6, 7, 8,
五六七八
5, 2...
五二
Are you done?
你们练完了吗
Beat it if you're done.
练完赶紧走吧
We need the court.
我们要用场地了
Hey, Jokester,
小笑话
take them with you and leave.
让你们班的人赶紧走
No!
不行
What did you say?
你说什么
It was clearly that we got here first.
明明是我们班先到的
My name is Xiao Xiaohua.
还有 我叫肖小画
Keep that in mind.
别叫错名字了
You've been using it for so long.
你们都用这么长时间了
It's our turn now.
该到我们了
Exactly.
就是
This place is pretty big.
这儿场地这么大
Can't you girls practice over there?
你们班去那边练不行吗
Why should we?
凭什么呀
You've been using it for so long!
你们都用这么长时间了
We just got here!
我们才来
You outnumber us, so what?
人多了不起啊
Even though it's been so long,
你们练了这么久
you haven't got any better.
也没看你们练好呀
Why hog the court?
占着场地干吗
It's our turn!
该到我们了
If you can't do it right, just quit!
练不好别练了呗
Bullying the few is unfair!
人多欺负人少是吧
Get lost!
让开
What's going on here?
干嘛呢
They've been hogging the court
他们一直霸占着场地
the whole time.
不让
What do you mean hogging?
什么叫霸占
It's our turn!
该到我们了
Ask them to leave!
那就让她们让呗
Why should we leave?
怎么让啊
Right.
就是
This isn't the private court
这又不是你们八班
of Class 8.
专用场地
Say that again!
你再说一句
So what?
再说就再说 怎么了
Can you all shut up?
能闭嘴吗
I told you to leave!
我让你们让开
Jinghui.
灰哥
Lan Jinghui?
兰靖灰
Apologize!
道歉
Come again?
你说什么
Apologize
我说让你
to our girls now!
给我们班女生道歉
What if I say no?
如果我说不呢
Lan Jinghui,
兰靖灰
I've put up with you for long.
我忍你不是一次两次了
Looking for an ass kicking?
皮痒了是吧
Come on!
来 来
Stop, stop!
好了 好了
You guys, stop!
停 别争执了
Are you going to fight?
这是要打架啊
What's going on?
怎么回事啊
Calm down!
都冷静一点
Ms. Chai,
柴老师
class 5 has been monopolizing the court.
五班一直霸占着场地
We need to practise as well.
我们也需要排练的呀
What? Monopolizing?
什么啊 什么叫霸占
It's a public place.
公共场合
Alright, stop!
好了 好了 别争执了
Which class
我问你们
was using the court just now?
刚才哪个班在用场地
Class 5.
我们班
Ms. Chai,
老师
we were using it,
本来是我们班在用的
but...
但是
Well,
那不就得了
you've practised
你们班既然
here already,
已经用过场地了
it's only fair that the next slot
那么接下来的时间
goes to
就该轮到别的班的
other classes.
同学了
But we haven't finished!
我们没练完呢呀
C'mon,
好了 好了
chill out!
不要有情绪了
Just take turns, OK?
咱们轮番用好吧
Class 8, come on.
八班的同学赶紧吧
Beat it!
赶紧走人吧
Despicable!
没品
Class 5, take a short break.
五班同学休息一会儿
Class 8, get on with your training.
八班赶紧训练吧
Hurry.
快点的
Don't let this upset you.
别影响你们心情啊
Just focus on your practice.
咱八班好好练 加油
Why did you stop me just now?
班长你刚才为什么不让我说啊
Class 8 was
他们八班
being unreasonable.
真是太欺负人了
Exactly.
就是
That Bi Peng is the worst.
最可恶的就是那个毕鹏
Despicable.
有没有品
Hitting girls?
打女生
If Ms. Chai hadn't shown up,
你看要柴老师不在
I'd have kicked his butt already.
你看我收不收拾他
C'mon,
行了 行了
do you wanna get expelled all together?
你们想被打包开除吗
Just
要是不想的话
try the best
就好好想想
to win the match.
怎么打赢比赛
Ling Dong is right.
凌冬说得对
We should be aiming to
我们现在就应该
beat Class 8 on the court,
在篮球场上打赢八班
then parade the trophy
然后抱着奖杯
around their classroom.
去他们班走一圈
Xiao Xiaohua,
肖小画
how come
你怎么现在说话
you sound different?
跟以前不一样了
Do I?
有吗
Let's focus on
还是好好想想
how we're gonna beat Class 8.
怎么打赢八班吧
It's easy to say.
说得容易
They're among the favorites to win.
八班可是夺冠热门啊
Don't boost their morale
别长他人志气
and undermine our own.
灭自己威风啊
We should recognize our improvement.
士别三日我们令当刮目相看
Cheer up!
要对我们自己有信心
Jinghui is right.
灰哥说得对
I should be the one holding
我就应该拿着
the championship trophy
冠军的奖杯
and slapping their faces with it!
去打他们的脸
Let's see how Ms. Chai
我看柴老师
react to that!
还护他们
Let's go.
走吧
Nice shot!
好球
What's happening?
什么情况
Watch your defense.
防住啊
Can't stop him.
防不住啊
So impressive.
真厉害
Ms. Fang,
方老师
what's all this?
你这都是些什么呀
The tournament
这不篮球比赛
is coming up.
马上要开始了吗
I prepared these items
我给我们班啦啦队女孩
for our cheerleading squad.
准备的道具
I think
要我看呀
all this preparation is unnecessary.
准备这些都是多余的
It distracts the kids
影响孩子们的注意力
and affects their studies.
影响他们的学习
I firmly believe
我倒觉得
that they should
他们该学习的时候呢
strike a good balance
就认真学
between learning
当然该玩的时候
and entertainment.
也要尽兴
What a young idea!
要不说你还年轻呢
My students are
我们班的学生啊
extremely self-disciplined.
就特别自律
I don't have to worry about them at all.
一点都不用我操心的
They're always focused,
该忙啦啦队的事
such as on the cheerleading
忙啦啦队的事
and winning games.
该赢比赛赢比赛
What fancy boys and girls!
我是一点心都不要操
I trust them completely.
我特放心他们
In my opinion,
要我说呀
Lan Jinghui,
你们班呀
the troublemaker
就不应该让那个
shouldn't lead the team at all.
胡闹的兰靖灰当队长
How can such an unreliable boy
他这么浑的一个人
take the lead
怎么带领团队
and manage a team?
怎么管理学生啊
Bravo!
好好好
Ms. Fang,
方老师
I'm talking to you.
我这跟你说话呢
Why do you keep zoning out?
你怎么老走神啊
Oh,
没有
Ms. Chai,
柴老师
I was just wondering
我刚刚呢 就是在想
what was the reason
您到底是出于一个
behind your statement?
什么理由要这样说
I didn't mean ill.
我没有别的意思
I know,
我知道
I don't have your experience,
我没有您资历老
and I'm still young.
我也还年轻
But I have a
但我跟你
different perspective.
有不一样的看法
Actually,
第一呢
I don't think
我不觉得
Lan Jinghui is a troublemaker.
我们班兰靖灰浑
Certainly, I don't believe
当然 我更不觉得
him being the team leader is a joke.
他当这个队长是胡闹
After all, you don't know him.
毕竟您不了解他
What reason do you have
您有什么理由
to definitively say he's not fit for it?
就一定要说他不行呢
Well...
这个嘛
This rain is getting heavier.
这雨怎么越下越大了
I'm going back inside.
我先回去了
Go! Lan Jinghui!
兰靖灰加油
Come on!
加油
Go, Class 5!
五班加油
Class 5 will win!
五班必胜
Overall, Class 1
一班他们整体实力
is mediocre,
是一般的
but they've got a few tall guys
但是对面那几个高个
who are tough to defend,
特别难防
especially their center.
尤其是他们那中锋
You need to press him.
要紧逼啊
Ma Yiming, Jian Zhiqiang,
马一鸣 简志强
you two will need to work closely.
到时你俩尽量配合
Be sure to minimize contact
但是尽量一定要减少
with the ball.
接触球
Keep him away from the penalty area.
让他远离禁区
Xu Chao,
许超
you will be the key for the game.
到时候比赛时候靠你了
Everyone, just relax.
大家都放松点
They're not as formidable as they seem.
他们也没那么可怕
Just play like we do
拿出平时训练的水平
in practice.
就行
Don't worry.
放心吧
We're never scared in the first place.
本来就没在怕的
We've got "Captain Chenjun" here.
有辰郡之光在
Alright, good luck!
行 加油
Class 5, go for it!
五班加油
Come on!
来
3, 2, 1,
三 二 一
Class 5, victory!
五班 五班 必胜
Go, go!
加油 加油
Go, Class 5!
五班加油 五班加油
Jinghui, here!
灰哥接球
Go!
好
Get back on defense, Ma Yiming!
回防 马一鸣
That's a foul!
犯规了
That's a legal charge.
合理冲撞
Go, go!
加油 加油
Class 1, go!
一班加油 一班加油
Do it!
加油
It's been three minutes,
开场三分钟了
we haven't scored yet.
一个球都没进
Both classes
他们两个班
have a strong desire to win.
求胜欲望都很强
If this keeps up,
这样下去
they'll burn out soon.
体力消耗会非常快的
Go!
加油
Go for it!
加油 加油 加油
With Ling Dong's shooting tips,
有了凌冬的投篮秘籍
our accuracy
我们的命中率
will improve greatly.
一定会大大提升
X equals 2PX,
X方等于2PX
P is greater than 0.
P大于0
F0 is one-half P.
F0二分之P
Y equals negative one-half P.
Y等于负二分之P
Give it another shot.
再试试
Head coach!
主教练
Who's the head coach?
主教练谁啊
Lan Jinghui...
兰靖灰
Yeah, Lan Jinghui.
对 兰靖灰
Coach.
教练
Don't leave.
教练 你别走啊
Help us!
再教教我们啊